

# HAORAN ZHENG

513-909-5366

raulzhenghaoran@gmail.com

♠ Chicago, IL, USA

AI RESEARCHER

## **ABOUT ME**

Motivated AI/ML researcher with a focus on Explainable AI.

Current Research Assistant at Epley Lab. Graduated with M.S. in Data Science from The University of Chicago with a 4.0 GPA.

Earned bachelor's degrees in
Economics, Finance, and History as a
triple major at The Ohio State University.
Experienced in teaching roles across
STEM fields, including Statistics.
Recipient of the Pace Setters Awards.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

SCENE: Evaluating Explainable AI Techniques Using Soft Counterfactuals

(Under Review) Aug 2024

#### **SKILLS**

Explainable AI Techniques

Programming Languages & Tools

Machine Learning Frameworks

Natural Language Processing

Causal Inference

Bayesian Methods

## LINKS

Personal Website: haoranzhengraul.github.io

**LinkedIn Profile**: www.linkedin.com

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Epley Lab**

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business Sep 2024 – Present

#### Mindworks Lab

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business Apr 2024 - Present

## Research Assistant in Behavioral Science

 Collaborate closely with Dr. Nicholas Epley and Yale scholar Yin Li on "The Multicultural Study," focusing on cross-cultural perceptions of beliefs and preferences.

# Research Specialist in Behavioral Science

- Collaborated with the University of Chicago Human-Robot Interaction Lab. Investigated the impact of personality alignment between humans and robots on the effectiveness of positive psychology exercises.
- Co-manage studies and collect data for renowned scholars like Dr. Nicholas Epley and Dr. Sarah Sebo.
- Examined frontier Behavioral Science research on prospect theory and diminishing sensitivity.

# Dr. Christopher Reed

The Ohio State University Apr 2024 – Present

## Research Assistant in History

- Applied modern NLP techniques and the SCENE method to traditional History research.
- Aim to identify the significance of previously unseen historical documents.

# The Ohio State University

Feb 2021 – May 2022

#### Lead Teaching Assistant for Statistics 2320

- Taught two weekly recitations for 65 students each, focusing on statistical concepts and analytic tools like R.
- Developed customized review notes and visual aids for 900+ enrolled students each semester.

## **EDUCATION**

# The University of Chicago

Chicago, IL 2024

#### Master of Science in Data Science

 Thesis: "Demystifying the Black Box: An Empirical Evaluation of Explainable Al Techniques in NLP Tasks" (Advisor: Dr. Utku Pamuksuz).

# The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH 2022

# Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

• Triple major in Economics (GPA 3.9/4.0), Finance (GPA 3.8/4.0), and History (GPA 3.8/4.0).